[Music]
hello everyone today I'd like to share
with you some information how we can
take advantage of the manual life
product and uh I would like to share
with you how you can utilize the
calculator to determine if the client
will be will benefit uh from this uh
product
so we have to input some information on
each item Home Savings debt cash flow
and we will be able to get the result
but don't worry for now uh we will
discuss with you some information later
on uh this is the URL I will send you
the link so you can play around uh on
your end later on okay so what I did I
created a sample scenario okay let's
consider this there's a married couple
John is the husband Mary is the wife
they're both making 6ou uh $33,000 each
net household income a combin of $6,000
every month now let's also consider this
scenario they their current home value
is
$800,000 their current balance is around
$400,000 uh their rate is$ 2.99 and
their bi-weekly payment is $920 every
month they currently have a checking uh
account of $33,000 and they also have a
savings of
$5,000 now let's consider this as well
uh the family has a credit card one
$5,000 balance $200 monthly payment at
19.5 interest rate credit card two
$7,500 balance ping $250 every month
19.5 interest rate as well they also
have a current loan of $225,000 balance
for $150 monthly payment at 4.99
interest rate they also have a personal
liner credit unsecured one $10,000
balance paying $300 every month
approximately 7 7% interest rate okay as
well we have to consider other other um
expenses in the family that heating cost
let's assume it's only $300 every month
$400 combined phone sell and cable again
this is only an estimate it could be
more or less but based on these numbers
let's see how it goes home insurance of
$150 every month uh also let's budget
$400 every month for for their um
restaurant expenses okay for the
groceries uh $20 every every day time is
30 days let's consider $600 every month
grocery expenses and gas of $400 every
month and a car insurance of $200 a
month okay so let's get right in okay so
let's input one by one so I already
input here
$800 $400 balance okay at a rate of$
2.99 interest rate okay they're paying
by weekly of
$920 okay every two weeks and then click
next you scroll all up let's talk about
the savings savings checking is
$3,000 uh the savings is
$5,000 right and then they they don't
assuming they don't have other
short-term savings so you click
next you roll this down credit card do
you pay off your credit card every month
let's just say no uh outstanding balance
is $5,000 as we mentioned earlier 19.5
interest rate paying $200 every month
$7500 on credit card to 19.5 interest
rate and a $250 every month you scroll
down let's talk about the car loan car
loan is
$25,000 at 4.99 paying $450 every month
let's see uh personal planer credit uh
$10,000 7% $300 every month let's assume
there's no personal loan no other loans
so you click
next next will be uh the household
income after taxes we we predetermined
the $6,000 combined from husband and
wife monthly mortgage automatic
calculation would be 199 1993. 33 total
that payments
$1,200 and uh uh what are your uh other
monthly household income expenses let's
say 1870 because we already
predetermined here
housing housing cost total we
determinate $300 on utilities $400 on
phone sell internet and cable $150 on
insurance okay and then uh for the
recreation we allocated $400 every month
for restaurant and meals uh daily
expenses uh because it says the
calculators daily so we calculated $20
okay times 30 days it's going to be $600
look at that number okay and then uh
that's it so you clear uh and then let's
go with the transportation let's
allocate $400 for the gas and Fuel and
insurance of the car around $200 every
month and let let's click
next boom Here's the final result okay
based on this result your manual life
one number
77807 this is the manual life number
with manual life you could save up to
77806 56 in interest cost and be debt
free in 10 years 10 months that is 12
years and 6 months earlier than your
current way so this calculator is very
powerful the bank uh the lender provides
this online accessible to everyone so
here's the comparison with the current
way uh of the current situation the
interest the total interest paid
automatically calculated
162,163
be debt free is 23 years and four months
compared to maximizing the power of
manual life the interest paid is only
84330 and 10 it could be debt free in 10
years and 10 months again this is only
an estimate but it's a very good uh tool
that we can present to our clients to
highlight the the beauty the advantage
of this program uh as well you can
um click this and it will show this
report okay you're in by cash flow and
it's allocation current way manual life
so it's already self explan
explanatory uh screen here okay so when
you go back
click save here go back there and then
you could also play around with this um
feature here let's say how much you
could save you can play around it it's
visually that's the time element factor
and the illustration all right so uh
overview go back there and then that is
how powerful manual life is I will also
provide you this um uh copy
okay and also for your reference the um
the actual report which is somewhere
right here with manual
life okay the result there okay pretty
much that's it so I hope you find Value
in this uh simple tutorial you have any
question don't hesitate to send me email
or contact me so we'll be able to help
out your clients have a great uh
wonderful day
[Music]